

Profile

Meticulous front-end engineer having more than 3.5 years of seasoned experience in software development. I'm passionate for developing modern, reactive, responsive and user friendly web applications and firm believer of mobile first approach. Adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfactions.

Employment History

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER ENGINEER, AVIZVA SOLUTION, GURGAON

JANUARY 2021 - APRIL 2023

Design and develop HTML, CSS, SASS, Material-UI, JavaScript , Redux, ReactJS, NextJs and TypeScript that meets accessibility and web browser standards for website.

Working on an Agile (Scrum) Development Team and involved in complete SDLC - Requirement Analysis, Development, System and integration Testing.

- Developing a Design Library which follows neumorphic design and mobile first approach.
- Aflac member portal (Insurance Dental & Vision)
- Argus Employee Portal (Insurance Dental & Vision)
- Create the Framework for the fronted using micro-application architecture.

Mentoring a team of 4 junior engineers by providing them feedback's and reviewing their code.

Assisted in A/B testing of different UX components that resulted in a 25% increase in customer conversion rates.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER, SHINE DEZIGN INFONET, MOHALI

JANUARY 2021 - JANUARY 2022

- Designed and developed the Web Application where user can compare and purchase insurance plans for their pets for a pet insurance company, PetPlan.
- · Developed the web streaming platform using webrtc
- Enhanced overall web application performance by optimizing the critical rendering path, reducing page load time and improving performance metrics such as FCP, FMP and TTI etc from 82% to 90%.
- Improved web application security by composing middle-wares to prevent various attacks such as CSRF, XSS, CSP and Click-Jacking etc which diminished the attacks from 7% to 4.2%.

JUNIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER, BUSIBUD SOLUTIONS PVT LTD, Mohali

OCTOBER 2019 - JANUARY 2021

Products Work upon: Mock Chat Admin, Employee Attendance Portal

Assisted senior developers in performing code reviews and implementing improvement plans.

Education

B.Tech: Computer Science, JMIT RADAUR, Yamunanagar

Details

GURGAON

India

7700969697

toshal.t1@gmail.com

Links

https://github.com/toshallubana

linkedin.com/in/toshal-lubana-79419a181

Skills

Java Script

HTML

CSS

REACTJS

Material UI

Redux Next.js

tailwind

TypeScript

Graphql

Apollo

NodeJs

Scss

MAY 2015 - JULY 2019

Board/University: UGC

Scored: 8 CGPA

Graduated with Honors

12th: Science, Govt. Model Senior Secondary School Sector - 8, Chandigarh, Chandigarh

JUNE 2013 - MARCH 2015

Board/university: CBSE, New Delhi

Scored: 80%

10th: Science, DAV Public School, Chandigarh, Panchkula

MARCH 2011 - MARCH 2013

Board/university: CBSE, New Delhi

Scored: 8.8 CGPA